alteclansing.com 2012-11-13

# Altec Lansing > Privacy Policy

### PRIVACY STATEMENT

Altec Lansing Technologies, Inc. ("Altec Lansing") is committed to protecting the privacy of consumers visiting our websites and purchasing our products. Altec Lansing wishes to maintain a safe and secure environment for all users of our online products and services. Please read the following Privacy Statement to understand how your personal information is treated. From time to time Altec Lansing may offer new products and/or services online which may affect this policy, which will be updated as needed. Please check back with us periodically.

This privacy statement covers WWW.ALTECLANSING.COM (herein after "Websites").

Altec Lansing Technologies, Inc. is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build users" trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. Because Altec Lansing wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe.[Note: Plantronics participated in the TRUSTe organization. This is not required. If Altec Lansing decides not to participate in the TRUSTe program, this paragraph and other references to TRUSTe should be removed]

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact the Altec Lansing Privacy Administrator by email at privacy@alteclansing.com.[Note: If another address is used, revise accordingly]. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry, or if your inquiry is not satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe through the TRUSTe Dispute Resolution Process at www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php. TRUSTe will serve as a liaison to resolve your concerns.

The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through the Websites, and does not cover information that may be collected through software downloaded from the Websites.

Altec Lansing complies with the EU Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union.[Note: Has Altec Lansing begun the process of complying with the EU Safe Harbor framework? It is not required, but is generally the easiest way to handle compliance regarding orders from the EU. This paragraph should be removed until Altec Lansing registers under the Safe Harbor framework.]

### This Privacy Statement answers the following questions for you regarding your online

### privacy protection:

  * • What Information Does Altec Lansing Collect?
  * • Does the Altec Lansing Website Use "Cookies or Clear GIFs"?
  * • Do I Have to Register With the Website?
  * • How Does Altec Lansing Use My Information?
  * • Does Altec Lansing Disclose My Personal Information?
  * • What About Security of Data Transmission?
  * • Can I Correct/Update the Information Collected About Me?
  * • Will You Notify Me in the Event of Changes to this Privacy Statement?

### Miscellaneous:

  * o Children’s Privacy
  * o Contests and Sweepstakes
  * o How Can I Opt-In/Opt-Out?
  * o Why Do I Need An ID and Password?
  * o Links
  * o Additional Information Disclosure
  * o How Do I Contact Altec Lansing?
  * o Your California Privacy Rights
  * o Legal Disclaimer
  * o Revision Date

### What Information Does Altec Lansing Collect?

Altec Lansing will collect personal information from our users for different purposes. Information gathered online can be identified as either anonymous or identifiable. Anonymous information is information that cannot be traced back to the individual. Identifiable information is information that is specific to the individual so that we can deliver the right products and services to the individual. The following lists the many ways in which we collect personal information from our users and the type of information collected:

To purchase products and to obtain other services offered on the Websites, a user has to provide certain information. Users may also register with the Websites and create ahis/her profile by completing a questionnaire online. Through the purchase process or by completion of the questionnaire by a user we collect the following information: (i) full name; (ii) address; (iii) phone and fax numbers; (viii) e-mail address; (iv) credit card information (not required for mere Website registration); (vi) user name; and (vii) password; and (vi) nickname. The provision of this personal information is mandatory and if you choose not to submit the requested information we will not be able to allow you to purchase products or provide you with the services offered on the Websites.

To register your purchased product online, we may request the following information: (i) full name; (ii) email address; and (iii) purchase date. The provision of this information is mandatory in order to register your purchase online. The provision of the remaining information requested on the product registration form is optional.

If you desire, you may participate in Altec Lansing" online surveys. If you choose to participate, we will collect anonymous information about the environment you work in, telephone habits, and demographic information. These surveys are developed in order for us to understand what types of products are most effective for our customers and to find the best ways to advertise to reach new customers. Your participation in our online surveys is entirely voluntary. Altec Lansing may provide gifts to those individuals who participate in surveys, and will request a mailing address to ship the gift. Altec Lansing will not use the mailing address or personal information for any purpose other than mailing the gift. You will be given the option to opt-in to receive further emails from Altec Lansing, including but not limited to marketing emails, advertisements, newsletters and bulletins.

If you choose to use the online “ask a question” type of support, the following information is gathered through the creation of an account or use of Email address: Email address, product, store of purchase, date of purchase, first name, last name, region. The information is viewable to the support person that is handling the question.

Altec Lansing may use mobile messaging, SMS campaigns to communicate with customers who have opted in to receive these types of communications. We will use a third party service to deliver the messages,. tThey have been advised that any personal information transmitted to them in order to transmit the campaign is the property of Altec Lansing and not to be used for any other means other than to carry out the transaction. The third party will verify your carriers" policies in regard to sending text messages, however if you believe you have received any messages in error, please contact us at privacy@alteclansing.com.

### SERVER LOG FILES:

As is true of most Web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and click stream data.

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users" movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information.

### Does the Altec Lansing Website Use "Cookies or Clear GIFs"?

We use cookies on this site. A cookie is a piece of data stored on a site visitor"s hard drive to help us improve your access to our site and identify repeat visitors to our site. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site. Additionally, we use cookies to track our online advertising efforts. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information on our site.

### Altec Lansing may use the following types of cookies:

• "Session" cookies expire upon exiting our site and closing all browser sessions.  
• "Non-session" cookies are currently set so that they do not expire after 30 days after using our site.  
• "Third-party" cookies, in particular Click-Track cookies, are used to track a user session. The information collected is not linked to the user"s personal information.

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If you would like to opt-out of these emails, please see "How Can I Opt-In/Opt-Out"

### Do I have to Register with the Website?

All users can access the Websites without being a registered user. However, you will not be able to access certain areas or obtain order history or status purchase our products online if you are not a registered online user.

Personal information collected by us to operate our business and, primarily, for the purpose it is collected, such as: to facilitate purchases online, to register users" purchases, to ask a question, or to process users" resumes. In particular, the users" shipping and billing addresses are used for fulfilling the purchase orders and to bill a user"s credit card. The personal information provided in a resume is used to consider the eligibility of the candidates. In addition to the original purpose for which the personal information is collected, we may use the personal information to contact users to confirm information related to his/her order, to advise a user if an item is on back order, for analysis and marketing purposes, and to generally manage and operate our business.

Altec Lansing also may use users" email address, mailing address, and/or phone number as follows provided that the user grants his/her consent to such additional use:

• In our internal surveys to obtain feedback on our products, our website, or on other aspects of our business that impact you as a Altec Lansing customer;  
• To notify users of new products or services we think may be of interest to them;  
• To send promotional materials.

We may also use personal information collected to contact users in connection with the inappropriate use of the Websites.

### Does Altec Lansing Disclose My Personal Information?

From time to time, we may disclose your personal information to organizations that perform services for or on behalf of Altec Lansing, for example to provide customer service, deliver products, ship items, process credit cards, for research, marketing, data processing, and to measure the use of our Site. We will share with these companies only that personal information which they need to work on our behalf. Some of these service providers may be located in other countries. Your personal information will be provided to these organizations only if they agree to use such information solely for the purpose of providing services to Altec Lansing, and under the instructions of Altec Lansing, and with respect to that information, to act in a manner consistent with the relevant principles articulated in this Policy.

### What About Security of Data Transmission

Please note that at www.alteclansing.com there is a form where you can transmit credit card information in order to complete a purchase transaction. Any time we ask for a credit card number, we transmit that credit card number in an encrypted format. We use industry-standard, SSL (secure socket layer) encryption and are PCI Data Security Standard Level 1 compliant. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, Altec Lansing cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

### Can I Correct/Update the Information Collected About Me?

You have the right to correct/update or delete any inaccuracies to the personal information collected about you at www.alteclansing.com. If you have registered, Yyou can make changes to your personal profile at any time by going to the "My Account" page on our website. You will need your Logon ID (user name) and password in order to access your personal information.

You may also contact us via email at privacy@alteclansing.com to request changes to your profile. Requests received via email will be acknowledged and responded to within 30 days of receipt

All access requests will be acknowledged and responded to within 30 days of receipt.

### Will You Notify Me in the Event of Changes to this Privacy Policy?

Altec Lansing reserves the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy. Any changes in the policy will be posted directly on the Altec Lansing website at www.alteclansing.com/privacy/. In the event of a material change in the site"s data collection and handling practices, Altec Lansing will post a prominent notice on the web site for 30 days.

We encourage you to review our Privacy Statement whenever you visit the Websites. If you have any questions or concerns on the Altec Lansing Privacy Statement, please contact privacy@alteclansing.com.

### MISCELLANEOUS

### Children’s Privacy

The Websites are not intended to be used by children. Altec Lansing does not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13.

Contests/Sweepstakes  
From time-to-time Altec Lansing may sponsor contests/sweepstakes on our site. Participation in these contests/sweepstakes is completely voluntary. Personally identifiable information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address) and demographic information (such as zip code). You will have the option in all of our contests/sweepstakes to "opt-in" or "opt-out" of receiving these special promotions etc. from Altec Lansing Technologies, Inc. and its advertisers, partners, affiliates, and sponsors (see How Can I Opt-In/Opt-Out? for more information). By entering, you agree to all of the terms and conditions, which will be clearly outlined in the rules. Where a contest or sweepstakes is not sponsored by Altec Lansing, the identity of the sponsor will be clearly disclosed in the rules. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of the sponsor before entering.

### How Can I Opt-In/Opt-Out?

We provide you the opportunity to opt-in to have your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information.

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication, by emailing us at privacy@alteclansing.com or you may contact us at Altec Lansing Technologies, Inc. c/o to opt-out.

### Why Do I Need an ID and Password?

At our e-commerce site we provide an area for you to store your billing address, and shipping addresses. This is your private information and you should keep it secure. We also require that you enter your Logon ID (user name) and password for accessing Order Status where you will view the details of products ordered from Altec Lansing.

### Links

This web site may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that Altec Lansing is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such other sites. We encourage our users to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by the Websites.

### Additional Information Disclosure

Altec Lansing may disclose your personal information to its affiliates who may use your information to the same extent as Altec Lansing may use your personal information under this privacy statement. Additionally, Altec Lansing may disclose your personal information in connection with a sale or other transfer of Altec Lansing’s business.

### How Do I Contact Altec Lansing?

If you have any further questions or comments regarding this Privacy Statement, you may contact us at privacy@alteclansing.com, or by any of the following ways:

Facsimile: 570-296-1412  
Mail: Altec Lansing Technologies, Inc.  
c/o Mitchell Wenger?  
535 Route 6 & 209

Milford, PA 18337

### Your California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of Altec Lansing who are California residents to request certain information regarding its disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email or write to the email or physical address in the “How Do I contact Altec Lansing” section of this privacy statement. At this time Altec Lansing maintains an “Opt-In/Opt-Out” policy for disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes and, under California Civil Code Section 1798.83, Altec Lansing may only be required to inform you of the mechanism to Opt-Out of disclosure for future third party direct marketing purposes.

### Legal Disclaimer

We may disclose personal information when required by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary in order to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with a legal process served on us.

### Revision Date

This Privacy Statement was last revised on: 07/01/10
